BRIAN K. WONG

917-815-2243 | bwong92@gmail.com | Portfolio Website | GitHub | Blog | LinkedIn |

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

With prior experience in Accounting and Finance, I bring strong teamwork, discipline, troubleshooting, and communication skills. While obtaining my master's degree, I discovered coding by taking data analytics courses. After exploring coding further, I became excited by solving algorithms and the creative process of web development. I look forward to combining my skills in Ruby on Rails, Javascript, and React, with my problem-solving strategies to launch a career in software engineering.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Abibas - Github | App

Built an application that allows users to purchase sporting goods online

- Designed and created database schema and RESTular API with Active Record, Postgres, Ruby on Rails
- Leveraged Redux and middleware for asynchronous data retrieval from the back end
- Utilized local storage, JWT Auth, and custom validations to create authorization and authentication for users
- Developed website utilizing Vanilla HTML/CSS to enhance presentation and enhance user experience

Better Than Trello - Github | App

A simple application built over 2-3 days that allows users to organize their projects

- Designed and created database schema and RESTular API with Active Record, Postgres, Ruby on Rails
- Utilized React and Vanilla CSS to build out the front end to ensure smooth user experience

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Ruby on Rails, SQL, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, React, Redux, Git, CSS, HTML, TDD; Familiar with: Python, React Native, WordPress

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

NYC Coders | Attendee March 2020-Present

- Explore how to use React Hooks and React Native by pair coding with other attendees
- Communicate with members in order to stay current with trends in popular tech platforms

NYC Coders Hackathon for Black Lives Matter | Jr. Developer/Hacker

June 2020

- Attended a 4-day event to develop solutions and bring awareness to the Black Lives Matter movement
- Collaborated with a team of 5 to produce a data visualization dashboard that displays NYC police shooting data
- Created components and structured the layout of the dashboard in React to demonstrate how clear the data is skewed

JP Morgan Inside Sherpa Virtual Internship | Intern

April 2020

Built financial graphs using Python, React, and Typescript to analyze and aggregate data

Techstars Global Online Startup Weekend Unite to Fight Covid-19

April 2020

Collaborated with a team to pitch a solution to assist local grocers without an online presence to generate sales

OTHER EXPERIENCE

SL Group, Brooklyn, NY | Private Equity Intern

Feb 2018-June 2018

- Identified and prepared summaries for private middle-sized companies that met the desired attributes for acquisition
- Provided financial statement analysis to assess targeted companies' business structure, as well as DCF's to project company outlook over 5 year period

Kings County Public Administrator, Brooklyn, NY | Accounting Consulting Intern

July 2017-Jan 2018

- Collaborated with a team to troubleshoot, reorganize, and establish internal controls to improve accounting procedures
 increasing a general fund from less than \$50K to over \$1M and better manage assets of a fiduciary fund of \$100M
- Reviewed high volume of data in documentation to verify accuracy of passed financial statements (going back four years) to reconstruct them for compliance with Governmental Accounting Standards Board

EDUCATION

Flatiron School, New York, NY | Fullstack program (SQL, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Active Record, Javascript, React, Redux) **Baruch College, Zicklin School of Business, New York, NY** | Master of Science: Accounting | GPA: 3.3 **SUNY Buffalo, School of Management, Buffalo, NY** | Bachelor of Science: Accounting

Dec 2019 May 2019

May 2015